Rienow, Leona; Papers mss025
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Typescripts, ca. 1952-1955; Undated; 1; 2 cubic ft.
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XL, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 97)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 98)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 99)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 100)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLIV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 101)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 102)
  - Monuments By God, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 103)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter I, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 104)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter II, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 105)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter III, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 106)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter III-A, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 107)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter IV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 108)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter V, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 109)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter VI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 110)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter VII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 111)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter VIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 112)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter IX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 113)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter X, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 114)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter XI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 115)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter XIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 116)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 117)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter XV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 118)
  - Pea Soup and Snails, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 119)
  - Peeking Gendarmes, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 120)
  - Professor Your Good Will is Showing!, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 121)
  - River Without Any End, Title Page, Author's Note, Chapter I, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 122)
  - River Without Any End, Synopsis, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 123)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter I, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 124)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter II, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 125)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter III, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 126)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter IV, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 127)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter V, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 128)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter VI, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 129)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter VII, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 130)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter VIII, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 131)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter IX, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 132)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XI, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 133)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XII, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 134)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XII a, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 135)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XIII, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 136)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XIV, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 137)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XV, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 138)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XVI, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 139)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XVII, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 140)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XVIII, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 141)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XIX, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 142)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XX, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 143)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XXI, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 144)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XXII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 145)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XXIII, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 146)
  - River Without Any End, Source Bibliography, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 147)
  - Screwball Authorities: Our Idolatry of Big Names, 1940 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 148)
  - Tourists Delight, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 149)
  - You Can't Buck Tradition, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 150)
  - Unbottled Scotch, 1987 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 151)
  - We Become Class-Conscious, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 152)
- Research Materials, 1856-1960; 2; 0.45 cubic ft.
  This series contains research materials that Leona Train Rienow used for her books, short stories, and articles. There are many whole newspaper sections pertaining to Duluth, Minnesota and mining in Minnesota, as well as Photostats of land records dating from the nineteenth century. There are also magazines and brochures, as well as drawings of floorplans, materials on the history of many towns in England, and interviews of miners, including her father.
  - Alfred, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Archaeology, 1937-1938 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Arts and Trade, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Atomic Peril, 1960 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Chronology, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Chronology of Reigns, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Churches and Nunneries, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Corrections, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Count, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Countryside, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Customs, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Danes, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Dress and Accoutrements, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Ethelfleda's Parents, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Ethelwulf, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Fleda, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Floor Plans, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - The Friar's Lantern, 1948 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Kent, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Laws, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Lemner Manuscript, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Life in New York-Driftwood, 1932 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Life in 10th Century Britain, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Locusts, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Logging, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - London, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Maps, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - McCarthy's Beach Project I, 1938-1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - McCarthy's Beach Project II, 1938-1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - McCarthy's Beach Project III, 1938-1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Medical Facts, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Mesaba Historical I, 1856-1948 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Mesaba Historical II, 1888-1958 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Mesaba Historical III, 1888-1958 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Mining, 1933-1936 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Minnesota, 1888-1939 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Minnesota, 1938-1939 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Moscow, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Poems and Ballads, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Peoples, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Pioneering, 1909-1947 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Politics, ca. 1950 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Popes, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Preparing Students for the Job Market, 1941 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Prince Valiant, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Resources, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - River Without Any End, 1935-1941 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Rochester, England, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Sapon Building, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Surveys, 1960 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Tappan, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Winchester, Wessex, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Youth Organizations, 1948-1949 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 53)
- Correspondence, 1946-1988; 3; 0.33 cubic ft.
  This series consists of letters exchanged between Leona Train Rienow and various editors and publishing houses in her search to get her works published. In some cases, there are both Rienow's letters and those of the editor or publisher. In other cases, only the editor's or publisher's letters remain.
  - The American Home, 1959 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Better Homes and Gardens, 1960 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - The Board of Education and Publication of the American Baptist Convention, 1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1963 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - The Children's Friend, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Children's Play Mate Magazine, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Christian Herald Magazine, 1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Doubleday & Company, 1950 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Every Woman's, ca. 1959-1960 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Girl's Fun and Fashion Magazine, 1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Girls Today, 1952-1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Good Housekeeping, 1959 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Harcourt-Brace, 1952-1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Harper's Bazaar, 1960 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - Hougton-Mifflin Company, 1946-1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Ives Vernon, 1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Jack and Jill, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - Julian Messner, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 1959 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - Lippincott, Company, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - List of Editors, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - Little Brown & Company, 1946-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - Longmans, Green & Company, 1946-1954 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 79)
  - Macrae-Smith Company, 1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 80)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 81)
  - The Methodist Church, 1949-1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 82)
  - Methodist Publications, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 83)
  - Oxford Books, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 84)
  - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 85)
  - Random House, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 86)
  - The Reader's Digest, 1959 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 87)
  - Redbook Magazine, 1959 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 88)
  - Leona Train Rienow, Biographical Information, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 89)
  - Scribner's Sons, 1947-1949 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 90)
  - Senior Prom, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 91)
  - Seventeen, 1950 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 92)
  - Simon & Schuster, 1951-1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 93)
  - The Star Weekly, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 94)
  - Story Parade, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 95)
  - Thomas & Crowell Company, 1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 96)
  - Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1946 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 97)
  - Vogue, 1959 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 98)
  - This Week Magazine, 1959 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 99)
  - The Westminster Press, 1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 100)
  - Whittlesey House, 1953 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 101)
  - William Morrow & Company, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 102)
  - Wing, J, 1988 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 103)
  - John C. Winston Company, 1948-1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 104)
  - Young America Magazines, 1948-1949 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 105)